Register of the National Committee on Food for the Small Democracies Records, 1939-1946
Hoover Institution Archives
- MEMBERSHIP FILE, 1939-1946
  - Kershner, Howard, 1943-1946
    - Speeches and writings
      - "Feeding Children in Nazi Dominated Europe," Congressional Record, 1944 May 4. Reprints (Folder 24)
      - "Nazi-Dominated Europe Starves," 1944 May 8 (Folder 25)
      - "French Food Need Stressed," New York Times, letter to the editor with Anne Morgan, 1944 June 15. Printed copy (Folder 26)
      - "Help For Suffering Children of Europe," 1945 May 4. Mimeographed copy (Folder 27)
      - "Merging Temporary Council With Save the Children Federation," speech, 1945 May 8. Typescript copy (Folder 28)
      - "Battered Belgium," 1945 September 30. Typescript copy (Folder 29)
      - "Kershner's Diary Pictures Plight of Children in Western Europe," New York Herald Tribune, 1945 November 25. Clipping (Folder 30)
      - "Holland Four Months After Liberation," Christian Science Monitor, 1946. Reprint (Folder 31)
      - "40,000 Child War Victims Still Suffer in Sweden," The SCF Bulletin, 1946 September. Printed copy (Folder 32)
    - Subject file, 1943-1946
      - American Friends Service Committee (Box 99., Folder 1)
      - Food Relief Campaign, London (Folder 2)
      - The Kershner Plan (Folder 3)
      - National Committee on Food for the Small Democracies
        - General (Folder 4)
        - Press releases (Folder 5)
        - Radio talks (Folder 6)
        - Resolutions (Folder 7)
      - Save the Children Federation
        - General (Folder 8)
        - Mailings (Folder 9)
        - Monday Morning Newsletter (Box 100., Folder 1)
        - Quarterly Bulletin (Folder 2)
      - Temporary Council on Food for Europe's Children
        - General (Folder 3)
        - Mailings (Folder 4)
        - Merger (Folder 5)
        - Minutes (Folder 6)
        - Press releases (Folder 7)
        - Publicity (Folder 8)
      - Miscellany (Folder 9)
  - Mc Cormick, Chauncey, 1940-1942
    - Clippings (Folder 10)
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 11)
      - Germany. Botschaft (United States) (Folder 12)
      - Great Britain. Embassy (United States) (Folder 13)
      - Poland. Ambasada (United States) (Folder 14)
      - Hoover, Herbert (Folder 15-16)
      - Hull, Cordell (Folder 17)
    - Subject file - Commission for Polish Relief, Inc. Agenda and minutes of meeting (Folder 18)
  - Pate, Maurice, 1939-1942
    - Correspondence
      - General
        - General (Folder 19)
        - Davis, Norman (Folder 20)
        - Germany. Botschaft (United States) (Folder 21)
        - Great Britain. Embassy (United States) (Folder 22)
        - Galpin, Perrin (Folder 23)
        - Hoover, Herbert. Includes H. B. Frese's essays on food situation in Europe (Box 101., Folder 1-3)
        - McCormick, Chauncey (Folder 4)
        - National Committee (Folder 5)
        - Richey, Lawrence (Folder 6)
        - Rickard, Edgar (Folder 7)
        - Tuck, W. Hallam (Folder 8)
      - Cables exchanged with "Foodcomm," "Polish Committee" and "Belgamcomm" (Folder 9)
      - Letters to the editor (Folder 10)
    - Speeches and writings (Folder 11)
    - Subject file - Commission for Polish Relief, Inc. (Folder 12)
  - Richmond, Raymond, 1940-1942
    - Correspondence. Includes clippings
      - General (Folder 13)
        - General
        - Farm publications (Folder 14)
      - Galpin, Perrin (Folder 15)
      - Garrette, Eve (Folder 16)
      - Hoover, Herbert (Folder 17)
      - Hoover, Herbert (Box 102., Folder 1-7)
      - Horner, Charles (Folder 8)
      - Rickard, Edgar (Folder 9)
      - Sawtelle, Raymond (Folder 10)
      - Tuck, W. Hallam (Folder 11)
    - Speeches and writings
      - Johnson, Edwin, Senator. Speech delivered in the United States Senate, 1941 March. Includes some correspondence (Box 103., Folder 1)
      - Richmond, Raymond. Radio broadcast, 1941 June (Folder 2)
    - Miscellany. Includes press releases and form letters (Folder 3)
  - Stephens, Dorsey, 1941
    - Correspondence (Folder 4-6)
    - Reports
      - "Food As a Counter-Weapon in the War" (Folder 7)
      - Food situation in Holland and Belgium (Folder 8)
  - Tuck, W. Hallam. Correspondence and clippings (Folder 9)
- SPEAKERS' BUREAU, 1941
  - Biographical data (Box 104., Folder 1)
  - Clippings (Folder 2)
  - Correspondence
    - General. Hamilton, Blanche, Director, Speakers' Bureau
      - General (Folder 3)
      - Hoover, Herbert (Folder 4)
    - Alabama, Arizona, Arkansas (Folder 5)
    - California (Folder 6)
    - Colorado (Folder 7)
    - Connecticut
      - A-G (Folder 8)
      - H-Z (Folder 9)
    - District of Columbia (Folder 10)
    - Florida, Georgia (Folder 11)
    - Illinois (Folder 12)
    - Indiana, Iowa, Kansas, Kentucky, Louisiana (Folder 13)
    - Maine, Maryland (Box 105., Folder 1)
    - Massachusetts (Folder 2)
    - Michigan, Minnesota, Mississippi, Missouri, Montana (Folder 3)
    - Nebraska, New Hampshire (Folder 4)
    - New Jersey (Folder 5)
    - New York City
      - A-L (Folder 6)
      - M-Z (Folder 7)
    - New York State (Box 106., Folder 1)
    - North Carolina, Ohio, Oklahoma, Oregon (Folder 2)
    - Pennsylvania (Folder 3)
    - Rhode Island (Folder 4)
    - South Carolina, South Dakota, Tennessee, Texas, Vermont, Virginia (Folder 5)
    - Washington, West Virginia, Wisconsin, Wyoming (Folder 6)
  - Informative material (Folder 7-8)
  - Invitations to speak
    - General (Folder 9)
    - Hoover, Herbert (Folder 10)
  - Lists of speakers and prospective speakers (Box 107., Folder 1)
  - Meeting and conference schedule (Folder 2)
  - Memoranda - Interoffice, 1941
    - Incoming
      - January-February (Folder 3)
      - March-April (Folder 4)
      - May-June (Folder 5)
      - July-October (Folder 6)
      - November-December (Folder 7)
    - Outgoing (Folder 8)
  - Resolutions of the United States Congress (Folder 9)
  - Reports (Folder 10)
  - Speakers' file
    - General
      - A (Folder 11)
      - B (Folder 12)
      - C (Box 108., Folder 1)
      - D (Folder 2)
      - E (Folder 3)
      - F (Folder 4)
      - G (Folder 5)
      - H (Folder 6)
      - I (Folder 7)
      - J (Folder 8)
      - K (Folder 9)
      - L (Folder 10)
      - M (Folder 11)
      - N (Folder 12)
      - O (Folder 13)
      - P-Q (Folder 14)
      - R (Box 109., Folder 1)
      - S (Folder 2)
      - T (Folder 3)
      - U (Folder 4)
      - V (Folder 5)
      - W (Folder 6)
      - XYZ (Folder 7)
    - Homan, Helen Walker
      - Correspondence
        - General (Folder 8)
        - Office (Folder 9)
      - Speeches and writings (Folder 10)
      - Trips file
        - Ohio (Folder 11)
        - West Virginia (Folder 12)
        - Wisconsin and Illinois (Folder 13)
  - Speeches and radio addresses
    - General
      - General (Box 110., Folder 1-2)
      - Carter, Boake (Folder 3)
      - Heyl, Ernest (Folder 4)
    - "American Forum of the Air" (Folder 5)
    - "People's Platform" (Folder 6)
    - "Town Meeting of the Air" (Folder 7)
- SUPPORT GROUPS, 1940-1946
  - Agriculture and farm groups
    - Correspondence, 1941-1943 (Box 111., Folder 1-2)
    - Press releases (Folder 3)
    - Statements of support of the NCFSD (Folder 4)
    - Subject file
      - Cornell University, Department of Agricultural Economics and Farm Management (Folder 5)
      - The National Grange
        - Correspondence (Folder 6)
        - Resolutions (Folder 7)
      - Opposition to the NCFSD (Box 112., Folder 1)
  - Labor groups. Files of Raymond W. Bellamy, Director, Labor Participation Division (Folder 2)
  - Religious groups
    - General
      - Correspondence
        - 1940
          - January-October (Folder 3)
          - November (Folder 4)
          - December (Folder 5)
        - 1941
          - January-February (Folder 6)
          - March-April (Folder 7)
          - May-July (Box 113., Folder 1)
          - August-September (Folder 2)
          - October-December (Folder 3)
        - 1942-1944 (Folder 4)
      - Director's files. Files of the Reverend Ben F. Wyland who reached religious groups and clergymen for support of the NCFSD in the form of resolutions and signed petitions
        - Biography (Box 114., Folder 1)
        - Clippings (Folder 2)
        - Correspondence
          - General
            - General, incoming and outgoing
              - A - G (Folder 3)
              - H - O (Folder 4)
              - P - Z (Folder 5)
            - Personal (Folder 6)
          - Executive Committee members Herbert Hoover, Perrin Galpin, and others, to and from Wyland (Folder 7)
          - Keller, Adolf, Director, Central Bureau for Relief of the Evangelical Churches of Europe (Folder 8)
          - Religious publications (Folder 9)
        - Form letters (Box 115., Folder 1)
        - Lists of names of religious leaders and clergymen (Folder 2)
        - Memoranda (Folder 3)
        - Opinions of the NCFSD by New York City clergymen (Folder 4)
        - Poster letter, "The Challenge to Christianity" (Folder 5)
        - Printed matter
          - General (Folder 6)
          - The Christian Century (Folder 7)
          - The Christian Science Monitor (Folder 8)
          - Christianity and Crisis (Folder 9)
          - Excerpts from Protestant magazines and newspapers
            - A-E (Folder 10)
            - F-Z (Folder 11)
        - Resolutions regarding feeding starving Europeans
          - Resolution 124, U.S. Senate (Folder 12)
          - Resolutions from churches (Folder 13)
        - Speeches and writings (Folder 14)
        - Statement of support of the NCFSD by religious leaders (Folder 15)
        - Subject file
          - Golden Rule Foundation (Folder 16)
          - Visit to the White House (Folder 17)
          - Miscellaneous (Folder 18)
    - Denominations. Correspondence unless otherwise noted
      - Baptist Church
        - Northern (Box 116., Folder 1)
        - Southern (Folder 2)
      - Catholic Church
        - General (Folder 3)
        - Ball, William C., Director, Catholic Participation Division
          - General (Folder 4)
          - Clippings (Folder 5)
          - Correspondence
            - A-L (Box 117., Folder 1)
            - M-Z (Folder 2)
          - Press releases (Folder 3)
          - Resolutions, petitions, endorsements (Folder 4)
            - Bishops (Folder 5)
            - Knights of Columbus (Folder 6)
      - Christian Science (Folder 7)
      - Congregational Church (Folder 8)
      - Disciples of Christ (Folder 9)
      - Episcopal Church (Folder 10)
      - Evangelical and Reformed Church and Evangelicalism (Folder 11)
      - Judaism
        - General
          - General (Folder 12)
          - Szoszkies, Henry (Folder 13)
        - Letters and press releases in support of NCFSD (Folder 14)
        - Publicity material
          - General (Box 118., Folder 1)
          - Goldstein, Abraham J., Director, Jewish Participation Bureau (Folder 2)
      - Lutheran Church (Folder 3)
        - General (Folder 4)
        - Eidem, Erling, Archbishop
      - Mennonite Church (Folder 5)
      - Methodist Church (Folder 6)
      - Presbyterian Church (Folder 7)
      - Society of Friends, American Friends Service Committee
        - 1940-1941 (Box 119., Folder 1)
        - 1942-1946 (Folder 2)
        - Miscellaneous (Folder 3-4)
  - Student groups - National Student Committee
    - Correspondence
      - General form letters (Box 120., Folder 1)
      - A (Folder 2)
      - Ba (Folder 3)
      - Barbour, Hugh (Folder 4)
      - Be (Folder 5)
      - Bo (Folder 6)
      - Br (Folder 7)
      - Ca (Folder 8)
      - Ch (Folder 9)
      - Co (Box 121., Folder 1)
      - Cr (Folder 2)
      - D (Folder 3)
      - E (Folder 4)
      - F (Folder 5)
      - Ga (Folder 6)
      - Go (Folder 7)
      - Ha (Folder 8)
      - He (Box 122., Folder 1)
      - I (Folder 2)
      - J (Folder 3)
      - Ka (Folder 4)
      - Kaufmann, Peter (Folder 5)
      - Ki (Folder 6)
      - La (Folder 7)
      - Lee, Charles Marston (Folder 8)
      - Lo (Box 123., Folder 1)
      - Lobenstine, Susan (Folder 2)
      - Ma (Folder 3)
      - Mc (Folder 4)
      - Me (Folder 5)
      - Mo (Folder 6)
      - N (Folder 7)
      - O (Folder 8)
      - Pa (Folder 9)
      - Ph (Folder 10)
      - Po (Box 124., Folder 1)
      - Pohlman, Vernon (Folder 2)
      - Q-Ra (Folder 3)
      - Rice, C. Leslie (Folder 4)
      - Richmond, R. S. (Folder 5)
      - Ro (Folder 6)
      - Sa (Folder 7)
      - Sc (Folder 8)
      - Schweiker, Hilda (Folder 9)
      - Se (Folder 10)
      - Sm (Folder 11)
      - Smith, Charles S. (Box 125., Folder 1)
      - Sn (Folder 2)
      - St (Folder 3)
      - T (Folder 4)
      - Tomara, Sonia (Folder 5)
      - U (Folder 6)
      - United Christian Youth Movement (Folder 7)
      - V (Folder 8)
      - Wa (Folder 9)
      - Waples, Christine (Folder 10)
      - We (Folder 11)
      - Wi (Folder 12)
      - Wo (Folder 13)
      - XYZ (Folder 14)
    - Office file
      - General (Box 126., Folder 1)
        - Administrative file
          - Director, Betty Jacob
            - Correspondence
              - General (Folder 2)
              - National Intercollegiate Christian Council (Folder 3)
              - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (Folder 4)
            - Memoranda (Folder 5)
            - Personal file (Folder 6)
            - Speech notes (Folder 7)
          - Mid West Representative, Helen Cummings. Correspondence
            - General (Box 127., Folder 1)
            - Iowa (Folder 2)
            - Minnesota (Folder 3)
            - Missouri (Folder 4)
        - Clippings (Folder 5)
        - Correspondence (Folder 6)
        - Expense accounts (Folder 7)
        - Mailing to 1000 names (Folder 8)
        - Radio broadcast transcripts (Folder 9)
        - Reports (Folder 10)
        - Resolutions (Folder 11)
      - Subject file
        - Meetings held. Activities are reported in press releases, memoranda and clippings (Box 128., Folder 1)
        - Opposition to the National Committee on Food for the Small Democracies (Folder 2)
        - Student Defenders of Democracy (organization) (Folder 3)
  - United States. Congress
    - General
      - Correspondence. Letters from the publisher of Pathfinder, A News Review of World Affairs (Folder 4)
      - Lists of names of Congressmen and mailings sent (Folder 5)
      - Publications - Congressional Record
        - General (Folder 6)
        - 1941
          - February (Folder 7)
          - March (Folder 8)
          - April (Folder 9)
          - May (Box 129., Folder 1)
          - June-December (Folder 2)
      - Resolutions - S.R. 124 and H.R. 245 (Folder 3)
    - House
      - Correspondence, arranged alphabetically by name of Representative
        - General
          - General (Folder 4)
          - Gibson, Hugh. Letter and replies (Folder 5)
        - A-F (Folder 6)
        - Buffett, Howard (Folder 7)
        - G-J (Box 130., Folder 1)
        - K-O (Folder 2)
        - P-Z (Folder 3)
      - Resolutions
        - H.R. 98 (Folder 4)
        - H.R. 117 (Folder 5)
        - H.R. 221 (Folder 6)
        - H.R. 244 (Folder 7)
        - H.R. 245 (Folder 8)
        - H.R. 3868 (Folder 9)
    - Senate
      - Correspondence, arranged alphabetically by name of Senator
        - General
          - Mailings to Senators (Box 131., Folder 1-2)
          - Tuck, W. Hallam
            - 1941 June 5 letter to Senators (Folder 3)
            - 1941 July 8 letter to Senators (Folder 4)
        - A-B (Folder 5)
        - Butler, Hugh A. (Folder 6)
        - C-D (Box 132., Folder 1)
        - Capper, Arthur (Folder 2)
        - Connally, Tom (Folder 3)
        - E-G (Folder 4)
        - George, Walter F. (Folder 5)
        - H (Folder 6)
        - Johnson, Edwin C. (Folder 7)
        - Johnson, Hiram (Folder 8)
        - K (Folder 9)
        - L (Folder 10)
        - Lodge, Henry Cabot (Folder 11)
        - M (Box 133., Folder 1)
        - Mc (Folder 2)
        - N (Folder 3)
        - O (Folder 4)
        - P (Folder 5)
        - R (Folder 6)
        - S (Folder 7)
        - T (Folder 8)
        - Taft, Robert A. (Folder 9)
        - V (Folder 10)
        - W (Folder 11)
      - Resolutions
        - S.R. 100 (Folder 12)
        - S.R. 124 (Folder 13)
  - Women's organizations. Files of Mrs. Courtland D. Barnes, Chairman, who solicited resolutions and signed petitions in support of the NCFSD
    - General (Box 134., Folder 1)
    - Correspondence
      - A-B (Folder 4)
      - C-D (Folder 5)
      - Davis, Dwight, Mrs. (Folder 6)
      - E-G (Folder 7)
      - Federation of Women's Clubs (Folder 8)
      - H-K (Box 135., Folder 1)
      - L-P (Folder 2)
      - R-S (Box 136., Folder 1)
      - T-Z (Folder 2)
      - Women's Christian Temperance Union (Folder 3)
      - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom (Folder 4)
      - Young Women's Christian associations (Folder 5)
    - Form letters
    - Resolutions
      - Women Urge Adoption of Senate Resolution #124 and House Resolution #245 (Folder 6)
      - Women Urge Adoption of Senate Resolution #124 and House Resolution #245 (Box 137., Folder 1-4)
    - Statement supporting NCFSD (Folder 3)
- OPPOSITION FILE, 1939-1942
  - Clippings (Box 138., Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence
    - General
      - A-B (Folder 3)
      - C-F (Folder 4)
      - G-H (Folder 5)
      - I-L (Folder 6)
      - M-P (Folder 7)
      - R-S (Folder 8)
      - T-W (Folder 9)
    - Clapper, Raymond (Folder 10)
    - Wall, Carl B. Includes clippings (Folder 11)
  - Lists of opponents and supporters (Folder 12)
  - Letters to the editor (Folder 14)
  - Rebuttals to opposition (Folder 13)
  - Pro-war material. Miscellany (Box 139., Folder 1)
  - Subject file
    - Academic institutions and academics (Folder 2)
    - Chicago Committee of Twelve (Folder 3)
    - Jewish religious groups (Folder 4)
    - Philadelphia Committee of Nine (Folder 5)
    - Protestant religious groups and leaders. Includes correspondence of Rev. Ben Wyland (Folder 6-7)
    - Van Dusen, Henry
      - Correspondence of and about him
        - General (Folder 8-10)
        - Galpin, Perrin and Hugh Gibson (Folder 11)
      - Writings (Folder 12-13)
- COUNTRIES FILE, 1933-1948
  - Africa. Correspondence and clippings, 1941-1943 (Box 140., Folder 1)
  - Albania. Correspondence, 1941 (Folder 2)
  - Argentina. Correspondence and clippings, 1941-1943 (Folder 3)
  - Austria - American Relief to Austria, Inc. Correspondence and clippings, 1945 (Folder 4)
  - Belgium. Mostly material relating to the Commission for Relief in Belgium
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 5-6)
      - Belgium. Ambassade (New York) (Folder 7-8)
      - Belgium. Ambassade (Washington) (Box 141., Folder 1)
      - Belgium. Consulat (New York) (Folder 2)
      - Bree, Firmin van (Folder 3)
      - Fonck, Charles (Folder 4)
      - Gutt, Camille (Folder 5)
      - Spaak, Paul Henri (Folder 6)
      - Zeeland, Paul van (Folder 7)
    - Press releases (Folder 8)
    - Printed matter
      - General (Folder 9)
      - Clippings (Folder 10)
    - Solicitation and publicity material (Folder 11)
    - Speeches and writings
      - Author unknown, "The Peril of Starvation" (Folder 12)
      - Bigwood, E., "The Food Situation in Belgium as of July 1941" (Folder 13)
      - Brown, Milton, "Was the Hoover Relief of Belgium a Success?" (Folder 14)
    - Student file (Box 142., Folder 1)
    - Subject file
      - Belgian-American Educational Foundation
        - General (Folder 2)
        - Printed matter. The Belgian Campaign and the Surrender of the Belgian Army
          - Typescript draft (Folder 3)
          - Printed copies (Folder 4)
          - Mailing list (Folder 5)
      - Belgian-American Relief Fund (Folder 6)
      - Belgian Committee in the U.S.A. (Folder 7)
      - Belgian Experiment (Folder 8)
      - Belgian funds in United States (Folder 9)
      - Belgian Gospel Mission (Folder 10)
      - Belgian Information Center (Folder 11)
      - Belgian Mission to the United States, 1941 May (Folder 12)
      - Belgians in Britain (Folder 13)
      - Committees - Palo Alto (Folder 14)
      - Food shortages. Miscellaneous material (Box 143., Folder 1-3)
      - Health conditions (Folder 4-5)
      - Missing persons (Folder 6-7)
      - Relations with Belgian government in exile and other officials (Folder 8)
      - Wilhelmina Fund, Inc. (Folder 9)
  - China, 1940-1943. Correspondence and clippings
    - General (Box 144., Folder 1)
    - China Famine Relief U.S.A., Inc. (Folder 2)
    - United China Relief (Folder 3)
  - Czechoslovakia, 1941-1943. Correspondence and clippings
    - General (Folder 4)
    - American Friends of Czechoslovakia (Folder 5)
  - Denmark, 1941-1942
    - Clippings (Folder 6)
    - Memoranda, reports, and interoffice correspondence of National Committee
      - General (Folder 7)
      - Report of American Friends of Danish Freedom and Democracy (Folder 8)
  - Ethiopia, 1940. Committee for Organization of Aid for Ethiopia (Folder 9)
  - Finland, 1939-1946. Mostly material relating to the Finnish Relief Fund
    - Correspondence
      - General
        - General, including cablegrams (Folder 10)
        - General, including cablegrams (Box 145., Folder 1)
        - Cablegrams, 1939 December-1940 July (Folder 2-3)
      - Finland. Consulate (New York) (Folder 4)
      - Hoover, Herbert and Paavo Nurmi, Taisto Maki, and Haimo Haitti (Folder 5)
      - Procope, H. [Finland. Legation (United States)] (Folder 6)
    - Printed matter
      - Clippings (Folder 7)
      - Fundraising and informational material. Includes Finnish Relief Fund and other relief organizations (Box 146., Folder 1)
      - White Book. Typescript excerpts (Folder 2)
    - Subject file - Frederiksen, Kirsten (Folder 3)
  - France, 1939-1945. Material relating to food packages and other aid
    - Memoranda, reports, and interoffice correspondence of National Committee (Folder 4-6)
    - Printed matter
      - Clippings (Folder 7)
      - Clippings (Box 147., Folder 1-4)
      - French Relief News (Folder 5)
    - Subject file
      - France Forever (Folder 6)
      - French Societies Council (Folder 7)
  - Germany, 1940-1946. Material relating to food situation in Germany
    - Clippings
      - Allied press (Box 148., Folder 1-2)
      - German press (Folder 3)
    - Memoranda and interoffice correspondence of National Committee (Folder 4)
    - Reports, charts, and miscellaneous information
      - General (Box 149., Folder 1)
      - "McDonald Report on Jewish Refugees, 1934." Typescript (Folder 2)
    - Subject file - American Friends of German freedom (Folder 3)
  - Great Britain, 1940-1944
    - Correspondence
      - General (Folder 4)
      - Great Britain. Embassy (United States) (Folder 5)
      - Foot, Dingle (Folder 6)
    - Printed matter and typescript reports re food situation in Europe and the British blockade
      - General (Folder 7-9)
      - Clippings (Box 150., Folder 1-2)
    - Subject file
      - American Committee for the Defense of British Homes (Folder 3)
      - British-American Ambulance Corps (Folder 4)
      - Bundles for Britain (Folder 5)
      - British War Relief Society and other aid for Great Britain (Folder 6)
      - Canterbury, Archbishop of (Folder 7)
      - Great Britain. Embassy (United States). Official policy statements and rebuttals of National Committee (Folder 8)
      - Lothian, Marquess of, British Ambassador to the U.S. Correspondence and miscellaneous printed matter (Folder 9)
      - Peace Pledge Union
        - General (Folder 10)
        - Posters issued by the Food Relief Campaign (Folder 11)
  - Greece, 1941-1945
    - Clippings (Box 151., Folder 1-4)
    - Memoranda and interoffice correspondence of National Committee (Folder 5)
    - Reports, charts, and miscellaneous information (Folder 6)